Volodymyr Dorosh

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Lviv. Ukraine

□ (+380) 67-513-3259 | vov.dorosh@gmail.com | sQverful | to



Summary.

Experienced Java Backend Engineer in enterprise applications development. Business value and the product-oriented person. Practice learner - interested in challenging tasks and learning new technologies or tools that could be applied in practice and bring effective business value. Have background sales management experience from a software product company.

Skills

Main Technology Java Core

Front-end HTML, CSS

Frameworks/Technologies Spring Framework: Boot, Data, MVC, Security, Batch, Shell; K8S, Docker, Hibernate, ActiveMQ/Kafka,

Flyway/Liquibase, Maven/Gradle, Keycloak, Flowable BPM, LaTeX

Testing Tools JUnit, Mockito, Karate, Postman, Swagger, Chrome DevTools

Bug Tracking Tools Jira, Sonar, ELK **Source Control** Git, Gitlab, Bitbucket **CI/CD** Jenkins, Gitlab pipelines

Databases PostgreSQL, MySQL

Languages Upper Intermediate in English, Intermediate in Polish, Native in Ukrainian

Experience

Symphony SolutionsSOFTWARE ENGINEER AT BYBLOS BANK PROJECT - IT ASSETS MANAGEMENT SOLUTION

Lviv, Ukraine

Dec. 2021 - Present

• Development of IT Assets Management Solution

- Responsible for the Java Application designed to generate diagrams of bank's infrastructure
- Proposed and rebuilt raw Java 8 application launched from main method to Spring Shell application with Java 17
- Refactored and stabilized application: 0 code smells, 0 vulnerabilities, 0 security hotspots.
- Integrated application with bank's CMDB using the Jira Assets Rest API
- Implemented new logic for generating diagrams of the whole bank's IT infrastructure
- Assisting in pre-sales processes
- Implementing PoCs: AWS Lambda with Jira's webhooks for creating infrastructure from Jira ticket, Architecture Dashboard for CTO on Spring MVC

SOFTWARE ENGINEER AT HANSECOM PROJECT - PUBLIC TRANSPORT TICKETING SOLUTIONS

- Development of the software solution for public transport. Java Spring applications on microservices architecture, deployed as K8S pods on AWS
- · Proposed and implemented solution for role-based security with documentation for further management.
- Introduced and developed a new microservice integrated with Flowable BPMN engine
- Extracted raw microservice in order to fasten further development of new components
- Implemented internal money wallet with transaction logging.
- REST API development: from OAS definition to covering implemented logic by unit and e2e tests.
- Managing Kubernetes & AWS S3 Bucket.
- Knowledge sharing assistance for new on-boarded engineers regarding project architecture, GitLab pipelines, development approach and etc
- Active participation in dev-talks and architecture discussions

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT VIDEOTRON PROJECT - BUSINESS SUPPORT SYSTEM FOR TELECOM SERVICE

Lviv, Ukraine

May. 2021 - Dec. 2021

PROVIDER

Etiya Inc.

- Development and maintenance of software applications designed for Telecom Industry
- Managing integration processes within different IT systems
- Deep down investigation, identifying the root causes of problems and resolving effectively
- Preparing technical documentations for projects & software applications

June 7, 2023 V.Dorosh · Curriculum Vitae

WebitelLviv, Ukraine

Sales Manager Feb. 2019 - Dec. 2020

- Achieved good personal reputation in partners network that led to receiving inbound leads from recommendations
- Managed and made a sale with company from Fortune 500 list
- Managing sales for CIS, Europe and US region
- Providing Customer Center and CRM solutions for Enterprise, products line: Creatio CRM, Webite IP-PBX
- Leads qualification identifying main tasks and problems of customers business
- Development of sales kit and strategies: presentations, key advantages, proof of concept, individual presentations, project road-maps
- Personal business trips for high prioritized customers
- Representing company and lead generation at conferences: Terrasoft Accelerate Global Conference, Bank Online MFO Summit

Education

Lviv Polytechnic National University

Lviv, Ukraine

BACHELOR'S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep. 2017 - Aug. 2021

- · Participated in organizing committee of CADSM International Conference
- Cumulative Avarage: 81.15%

Lviv Polytechnic National University

Lviv, Ukraine

MASTERS'S IN COMPUTER AIDED DESIGN AND DRAFTING

Sep. 2021 - Jan. 2023

Extracurricular Activity _

Logos IT Academy

Lviv, Ukraine

MENTOR

- Mentoring course Java Developer.
- Lecturing, reviewing code.
- Preparing code examples and tests.

EPAM Systems (Java Laboratory 28)

Lviv, Ukraine

Nov. 2020 - May. 2021

Sep. 2022 - Oct. 2022

• Gained theoretical knowledge and practical skills with Java Core.

- Practice with JUnit, Mockito, JDBC, H2
- Implemented XML parsers: DOM, SAX, STAX
- Studied OOP, GRASP/SOLID principles and GoF design patterns
- Developed personal web-project that helps in managing tests & questionnaires. Developed on Servlets and JSP pages, without frameworks, published on my github account.
- Refactored personal project by using Spring and RESTful services.

CAD Department of Lviv Polytechnic

Lviv, Ukraine

CONSULTANT

STUDENT

Sep. 2020

- Assisted in creating new curriculum subject "Methods of Business Communications".
- Shared my Sales Management commercial experience and recommended literature with professors.
- Prepared curriculum practicum tasks as laboratory works.

15th CADSM Conference by CAD Department of Lviv Polytechnic

Lviv, Ukraine

MEMBER OF ORGANIZING COMMITTEE

Sep. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- Created an Instagram account @cadsm_conference.
- Developed and managed content, grew audience.
- Gathered e-mail list of potential interested universities for the marketing campaign.

Ternopil Without Problems Hackaton

Ternopil, Ukraine

PARTICIPANT

May. 2018

- Co-creator of the concept of "AR Reproduction of the Destroyed Historical Architectural Heritage" in order to solve the problem of tourism in Ternopil.
- Presentation and speech composer, represented team and solution in front of the audience.

Personal Info.

HOBBIES

- Fond of running and sports events in love with half-marathons and spartan races with obstacles.
- Playing guitar, have experience of music distribution.
- Interested in mastering engineering skills and becoming a young CTO:)

PERSONAL CHARACTERISTICS

- Open-minded, hardworking, communicative, self-motivated, and responsible person.
- Appreciate the team's honesty, result-oriented and healthy team environment for effective teamwork.